(Returning Pearl)
(اللؤلؤة العائدة)
Xiao Yan Zi is a vulgar and cunning girl.
شياو يان زي هي فتاة مبتذلة وماكرة.
But just using Lin Er alone might not be enough.
لكن استخدام Lin Er وحده قد لا يكون كافيا.
Your Majesty, are you suggesting...
جلالتك، هل تقترح...
Yuan is dashing and promising.
يوان هو شخص وسيم وواعد.
Lord Jing is of the Ula Nara bloodline.
اللورد جينغ هو من سلالة أولا نارا.
He's far too good for the likes of Xiao Yan Zi.
إنه جيد جدًا بالنسبة لأمثال شياو يان زي.
Once Xiao Yan Zi becomes your daughter-in-law,
بمجرد أن تصبح شياو يان زي زوجة ابنك،
you can mold her and control her
يمكنك تشكيلها والتحكم بها
however you wish.
كما تشاء.
If that child could become a son-in-law of the royal family,
إذا استطاع هذا الطفل أن يصبح صهرًا للعائلة المالكة،
I will have done my duty by my sister.
سأكون قد أديت واجبي تجاه أختي.
Yes, Your Majesty.
نعم جلالتك.
If their plan succeeds,
إذا نجحت خطتهم،
things will be even more of a mess!
الأمور سوف تصبح أكثر فوضوية!
No way.
مستحيل.
Lord Jing
اللورد جينغ
is my life-saving insurance, okay?
هذا هو التأمين المنقذ لحياتي، أليس كذلك؟
I can't let him break up Xiao Yan Zi and Fifth Prince!
لا أستطيع أن أسمح له بتفريق شياو يانزي والأمير الخامس!
They're about to have physical contact! No!
إنهم على وشك أن يكون هناك اتصال جسدي! لا!
Princess Huan Zhu!
الأميرة هوان تشو!
Here.
هنا.
It's okay now.
لا بأس الآن.
What does "okay" mean?
ماذا يعني "حسنا"؟
It means, "oh, it's good."
وهذا يعني "أوه، إنه جيد".
It's a compliment.
إنها مجاملة.
Now, try it.
الآن، جربه.
- So? - It's so good!
- إذن؟ - إنه جيد جدًا!
It's okay! Very okay!
لا بأس! لا بأس جدًا!
Oh, it's good.
أوه، إنه جيد.
I've never tasted anything this good, not in the palace or out there.
لم أتذوق أي شيء جيد مثل هذا من قبل، لا في القصر ولا هناك.
Does it have a name?
هل له اسم؟
I'm sorry, Xiao Yan Zi.
أنا آسف، شياو يان زي.
I've wasted too many words talking to you.
لقد أهدرت الكثير من الكلمات في التحدث إليك.
I've got an idea.
لقد حصلت على فكرة.
It's called Lin's Bubble Milk Tea!
يُطلق عليه اسم شاي حليب الفقاعات من لين!
Lin's Bubble Milk Tea.
شاي حليب الفقاعات من لين.
Anyway, the important thing is, I'm finally free of that Nanny Rong!
على أية حال، الشيء المهم هو أنني أخيرًا حر من تلك المربية رونغ!
Your Highness, Nanny Rong may be strict,
صاحب السمو، قد تكون المربية رونغ صارمة،
but she's a senior in the palace.
لكنها كبيرة في القصر.
You would do well to learn from her.
سيكون من الجيد أن تتعلم منها.
I can learn!
انا استطيع التعلم!
But can't I learn from someone else?
ولكن هل لا أستطيع أن أتعلم من شخص آخر؟
Nanny Rong is terrifying!
المربية رونغ مرعبة!
How about this? I'll learn from Consort Ling.
ماذا عن هذا؟ سأتعلم من كونسورت لينغ.
She's beautiful and kind. I like her.
إنها جميلة ولطيفة. أنا أحبها.
What about Fifth Prince?
ماذا عن الأمير الخامس؟
How about you learn from His Highness?
ماذا عن أن تتعلم من سموه؟
I mean, you could have Fifth Prince teach you. How about it?
أعني، بإمكانك أن تطلب من الأمير الخامس أن يُعلّمك. ماذا عن ذلك؟
Fifth Prince?
الأمير الخامس؟
You mean the one who shot me with an arrow?
هل تقصد الذي أطلق علي السهم؟
I'm being polite by not cracking his head open!
أنا أكون مهذبًا بعدم فتح رأسه!
That was just an unfortunate misunderstanding.
لقد كان مجرد سوء فهم مؤسف.
Fifth Prince is a great man.
الأمير الخامس رجل عظيم.
His Highness is His Majesty's favourite son.
صاحب السمو هو الابن المفضل لجلالة الملك.
His Majesty is very wise.
جلالته حكيم جداً.
So if he favors him, how could he possibly be bad?
فإذا كان يفضله فكيف يمكن أن يكون سيئًا؟
Isn't that right?
أليس هذا صحيحا؟
Why are you looking at Lord Jing
لماذا تنظر إلى اللورد جينغ؟
when you're talking to me?
عندما تتحدث معي؟
I twisted my neck when I fell earlier. It's stuck.
لقد التويت رقبتي عندما سقطتُ سابقًا. إنها عالقة.
- I'll adjust it for you. - No need!
- سأعدلها لك. - لا حاجة!
Thank you.
شكرًا لك.
Your Highness,
صاحب السمو،
Her Majesty has asked me to find you
لقد طلبت مني جلالتها أن أجدك
some beginner-level books to start with.
بعض الكتب للمبتدئين للبدء بها.
As a newcomer to the palace, there is much to learn.
كوافد جديد إلى القصر، هناك الكثير لنتعلمه.
A solid foundation is essential.
إن الأساس المتين ضروري.
How thoughtful of you, Lord Jing.
كم أنت لطيف ومدروس، يا سيد جينغ.
I can't read.
لا أستطيع القراءة.
I believe that with diligence and a desire to learn,
أعتقد أنه مع الاجتهاد والرغبة في التعلم،
you will make progress in due time.
سوف تحرز تقدما في الوقت المناسب.
Well, Lord Jing can certainly help with that.
حسنًا، يمكن للورد جينغ بالتأكيد المساعدة في ذلك.
His nickname in the palace is
لقبه في القصر هو
the "Living King of Hell,"
"الملك الحي للجحيم"
The Living King of Hell?
الملك الحي للجحيم؟
When I was in the Laundry Bureau,
عندما كنت في مكتب الغسيل،
I saw him execute an old nanny right on the spot!
لقد رأيته يعدم مربية عجوز على الفور!
He executed her on the spot!
لقد أعدمها على الفور!
There was a family in the northern suburbs.
كانت هناك عائلة في الضواحي الشمالية.
The daughter never wanted to be a palace maid,
لم ترغب ابنتي أبدًا في أن تكون خادمة في القصر،
but her father, blinded by money,
لكن والدها، أعمى المال،
used Nanny Song's connections
استخدمت اتصالات المربية سونغ
to force her into service.
لإجبارها على الخدمة.
For three years, the girl's monthly stipend was taken by Nanny Song.
لمدة ثلاث سنوات، كانت المربية سونغ تأخذ راتب الفتاة الشهري.
In the end, the girl could bear it no longer
في النهاية لم تعد الفتاة قادرة على تحمل الأمر
and threw herself down a well.
وألقت بنفسها في البئر.
Your Highness,
صاحب السمو،
do you think Nanny Song's death was unjust?
هل تعتقد أن موت المربية سونغ كان ظالمًا؟
Not all all! She deserved it!
ليس كل شيء! لقد استحقت ذلك!
The palace may appear peaceful on the surface,
قد يبدو القصر هادئًا على السطح،
but in reality, there is danger everywhere.
لكن في الواقع، هناك خطر في كل مكان.
You are new here, Your Highness.
أنت جديد هنا، سموكم.
You must be cautious
يجب عليك أن تكون حذرا
and not let yourself be deceived by those with ill intentions.
ولا تنخدعوا بأصحاب النوايا السيئة.
Being able to make a friend like you in the palace is a blessing.
إن القدرة على تكوين صديق مثلك في القصر هي نعمة.
Don't worry, Lord Jing.
لا تقلق يا سيد جينغ.
I'll listen to you and study hard.
سأستمع إليك وأدرس بجد.
Good.
جيد.
Those sparkling, admiring eyes are supposed to be for Fifth Prince!
من المفترض أن تكون هذه العيون المتألقة والمعجبة مخصصة للأمير الخامس!
How has the plot gotten so derailed?
كيف أصبحت المؤامرة خارجة عن مسارها؟
Looks like the first step to fixing this story
يبدو أن هذه هي الخطوة الأولى لإصلاح هذه القصة
is to make Xiao Yan Zi dislike Jing Yuan.
إنه جعل Xiao Yan Zi يكره Jing Yuan.
You look so harmless,
تبدو غير مؤذية للغاية،
but you're quite manipulative, huh?
لكنك متلاعب إلى حد ما، أليس كذلك؟
Yuan, Princess Huan Zhu has only just entered the palace.
يوان، الأميرة هوان تشو دخلت القصر للتو.
You must look after her well.
يجب عليك الاعتناء بها جيدا.
What is he writing?
ماذا يكتب؟
A love letter?
رسالة حب؟
For who?
لمن؟
Could it be for Xiao Yan Zi?
هل يمكن أن يكون ذلك لشياو يان زي؟
You're the first person brave enough
أنت أول شخص شجاع بما فيه الكفاية
to spy outside my window.
للتجسس خارج نافذتي.
Go back.
عُد.
And don't do it again.
ولا تفعل ذلك مرة أخرى.
Why did you reach out your hand?
لماذا مددت يدك؟
I need to talk to you.
أريد أن أتحدث معك.
Come in.
ادخل.
You...
أنت...
I'm going to get something on you
سأحصل على شيء عليك
and expose your true colors.
وكشف ألوانك الحقيقية.
It's improper for a man and a woman to be alone in a room at this hour.
لا يجوز لرجل وامرأة أن يتواجدا بمفردهما في غرفة في هذا الوقت.
So whatever you have to say, say it quickly.
لذلك مهما كان ما تريد قوله، قله بسرعة.
What's the matter?
ماذا جرى؟
Are you scared?
هل انت خائفة؟
I'm not going to bite you.
لن أعضك.
Bedside reading...
القراءة بجانب السرير...
Don't tell me you're...
لا تخبرني أنك...
I'm going to expose you!
سأفضح أمرك!
I'm here to borrow a book.
أنا هنا لاستعارة كتاب.
That one.
هذا.
Why would a palace maid be studying military strategy?
لماذا تدرس خادمة القصر الإستراتيجية العسكرية؟
Military strategy?
الاستراتيجية العسكرية؟
(The Art of War)
(فن الحرب)
I should've known.
كان ينبغي لي أن أعرف.
When I was little,
عندما كنت صغيرا،
The Art of War
فن الحرب
was my father's favorite book.
كان الكتاب المفضل لوالدي.
But before he could finish teaching me,
ولكن قبل أن يتمكن من الانتهاء من تعليمي،
he passed away.
لقد توفي.
My father, too.
والدي أيضا.
If you want this book,
إذا كنت تريد هذا الكتاب،
I'll lend it to you.
سأقرضه لك.
What did you say?
ماذا قلت؟
I said
قلت
don't ask questions you shouldn't.
لا تسأل أسئلة لا ينبغي عليك طرحها.
These practice sheets
هذه أوراق التدريب
are clearly meant for a beginner.
من الواضح أنها مخصصة للمبتدئين.
These are for Princess Huan Zhu, aren't they?
هذه مخصصة للأميرة هوان تشو، أليس كذلك؟
That's none of your concern.
هذا لا يعنيك .
Everyone in the palace knows
الجميع في القصر يعرفون
you and I are a couple.
أنت وأنا زوجان.
If you're seen fawning over Her Highness,
إذا شوهدت وأنت تتملق صاحبة السمو،
you'll be known as a two-timing scoundrel.
سوف تكون معروفًا بأنك المحتال ذو التوقيتين.
You...
أنت...
So...
لذا...
I'll deliver these for you.
سأسلمها لك.
That way, your precious reputation remains intact.
بهذه الطريقة، ستبقى سمعتك الثمينة سليمة.
Bye!
الوداع!
Wait.
انتظر.
Use the door.
استخدم الباب.
I'll keep it quiet.
سأبقي الأمر هادئا.
Outrageous! This is utterly disgraceful!
أمرٌ مُشينٌ للغاية!
Sir, why are you so angry?
سيدي لماذا أنت غاضب هكذا؟
Look, the turtle's drawn really well!
انظر، لقد تم رسم السلحفاة بشكل جيد حقًا!
- Your Highness! - Xiao Yan Zi.
- صاحب السمو! - شياو يان زي.
You can't scribble on your practice sheet.
لا يمكنك الكتابة على ورقة التدريب الخاصة بك.
- Apologize to Mister Ji at once. - I didn't draw this.
- اعتذر للسيد جي على الفور. - أنا لم أرسم هذا.
I got this from Lord Jing. I didn't even open it.
حصلتُ على هذا من اللورد جينغ. لم أفتحه حتى.
I have to get the plot back on track.
يجب علي أن أعيد المؤامرة إلى مسارها الصحيح.
I'm sorry for setting you up,
أنا آسف لأنني أزعجتك،
Xiao Yan Zi.
شياو يان زي.
I'm sure Fifth Prince will help you out.
أنا متأكد من أن الأمير الخامس سوف يساعدك.
Such mischief!
مثل هذا الأذى!
You're to copy the Three Character Classic a hundred times.
يتعين عليك نسخ الكلاسيكية المكونة من ثلاث شخصيات مائة مرة.
A hundred times?
مائة مرة؟
- But I... - Mister Ji, Xiao Yan Zi's injury hasn't fully healed.
- ولكنني... - سيد جي، إصابة شياو يان زي لم تلتئم بشكل كامل.
- Look at Fifth Prince. - I'll take the punishment for her.
- انظر إلى الأمير الخامس. - سأتحمل العقوبة من أجلها.
See how good Fifth Prince is to you?
هل ترى مدى روعة الأمير الخامس بالنسبة لك؟
Not like Jing Yuan, who got you scolded and punished.
ليس مثل جينغ يوان، الذي جعلك توبخ وتعاقب.
Whoever framed Her Highness knows perfectly well who they are.
من قام بإيقاع صاحبة السمو يعرف جيداً من هم.
Sharp ears.
آذان حادة.
Sir.
سيد.
The princes and princesses exclusively use the high-quality tribute ink
يستخدم الأمراء والأميرات حبر التكريم عالي الجودة حصريًا
from the Imperial Household, ideal for calligraphy and painting.
من العائلة الإمبراطورية، مثالية للخط والرسم.
Burdened with official duties,
مثقل بالواجبات الرسمية،
I use the more common pine soot ink for writing.
أستخدم حبر السخام الصنوبري الأكثر شيوعًا للكتابة.
However, the person who drew this turtle
ومع ذلك، فإن الشخص الذي رسم هذه السلحفاة
used the most ordinary Hui ink found in the palace.
استخدم حبر هوي الأكثر شيوعًا الموجود في القصر.
So someone pretended to be Jing Yuan
لذلك تظاهر شخص ما بأنه جينغ يوان
just to frame Xiao Yan Zi.
فقط لتأطير شياو يان زي.
Yes. Who would do such a thing?
نعم. من يفعل مثل هذا الشيء؟
And with what motive?
وبأي دافع؟
It was me!
لقد كنت انا!
Sir, I drew the turtle.
سيدي، لقد رسمت السلحفاة.
I'll accept the punishment!
سأقبل العقاب!
Hang on...
إنتظر...